(ヤマト)やっぱり ここだったね。
I knew you'd be here.
(サイ)さすがは
火影直属の 暗部ですね。
I'd expect no less from
the Anbu Black Ops...
under the direct command
of the Hokage.
あの死体で 騙せないなんて…。
To think I wouldn't be able
to deceive you with that corpse...
どういうことか 詳しく聞こうか？
Now tell us everything.
What's this about?
Bonds
(ナルト)テメエは！
なんで オレたちを裏切った!?
You jerk!
Why did you betray us?!
ここで
あんまり 騒がないほうがいいよ。
You shouldn't make too much
of a commotion here.
厄介なことに なるから…。
Things will get troublesome,
you see.
クッ！ このやろう…！
- You jerk!
- Naruto!
(サクラ)ナルト！
ほら… これ…。
Here...take this.
アンタのでしょう？
It's yours, isn't it?
(サイ)ありがとう…。
Thank you.
ダンゾウからの 命令なんでしょう？
It was an order
from Danzo, right?
ダンゾウは 大蛇丸と組んで➡
Danzo has teamed up
with Orochimaru...
何かを しようとしてる。
and is attempting
to do something...
(サクラ)その ダンゾウと大蛇丸のパイプ役に
あなたが 選ばれた。
You were chosen
to be the go-between...
for Danzo and Orochimaru.
何を たくらんでるの!?
What're they planning...?
(ヤマト)大蛇丸と もう一度…➡
With Orochimaru, he's planning to...
木ノ葉崩しを 企ててるね？
once again destroy the Leaf Village...
そうだろう？
Isn't that right?
いえ… 違いま…。
No, that's not--
I can tell right away that
your smile is a lie!
お前の笑顔は ウソだって
すぐに わかる！
お前の 言ってることも
ウソは すぐ わかんだってばよ！
And I can tell right away that
what you're saying is a lie!
あなたたちに
ボクが 見つかってしまった時点で➡
Now that you have found me...
ボクの任務は
失敗ってことに なりますね。
my mission is considered
a failure.
(サイ)ボク１人で あなたたち全員は
始末できませんし…。
I can't handle all of
you guys by myself...
それに…
そこまで わかってるなら➡
And...if you know that much...
隠しても しかたないですね…。
then there's no point
in hiding anything.
そのとおりですよ。
You're exactly right.
ボクたちは 今の木ノ葉を潰す。
We're going to crush
the current Leaf Village.
なんだと!?
Say what...?!
木ノ葉を潰すために
大蛇丸に 取り入り➡
The real mission I was given was
to gain the favor of Orochimaru...
結託の きっかけ作りをするのが➡
and create an opportunity for
a collaboration...
ボクに与えられた 本当の任務です。
in order to crush the Leaf Village.
Do you know
what you're saying?!
お前！ 自分が なに言ってんのか
わかってんのか!?
そんなこと…！
それだけじゃない。
- To do such a thing--
- That's not all.
大蛇丸の情報を
こっそり ダンゾウ様に送る役目…。
I also have the duty
of secretly sending...
information about Orochimaru
to Lord Danzo...
つまり… スパイとしての任務も
おびてるんですよ。
In other words, I have also been
entrusted with a mission as a spy.
その調子で 続けろ。
Keep going.
隠してることは 全部 吐くんだ。
Own up to everything
you're hiding.
(サクラ)それって 要するに…➡
So basically what
you're saying is...
while proposing the collaboration
with Orochimaru...
大蛇丸相手に
結託を 申し入れつつ➡
出し抜こうってわけ？
you're trying to outflank him?
そんな 危ない役目を…。
You've been given such
a dangerous mission...
木ノ葉が 潰れれば➡
Orochimaru will definitely betray us...
once the Leaf Village
has been crushed.
大蛇丸は 必ず
裏切ってくるだろうからね…。
いつでも こちらが 優位に
立てるようにしておくためだよ。
It's to make sure we've always
got the advantage.
なるほどな…。
I get it...
ダンゾウは 木ノ葉を
自分のものにしたいのね。
Danzo wants to make
the Leaf Village his own, huh?
あなたは たった一人で
そのための手回しを？
You made preparations
for that all by yourself...
The information I wrote
in black ink
(サイ)ボクが 墨で書いた情報は➡
transforms into small animals...
それ自体が
小動物のように変化し➡
自分の身を守りながら 情報を
外へ 持ち出してくれますから。
and carries the information out
while protecting itself, you see.
ボクは この能力を買われて
この任務に 抜擢されたんだよ。
This ability of mine
was valued highly...
and so I was selected
for this mission.
木ノ葉が荒れれば
また 多くの人が死ぬ！
Many people will die, once again...
if things become turbulent
in the Leaf Village!
あなたの やろうとしてることが➡
Do you even know why
you're doing this?!
どういうことなのか
わかってるの？
No idea...
They're my orders, so...
さぁ…？ 命令だからね。
サイ… あなた…。
Sai, you...
(サイ)もうひとつ言うと
サイという名は➡
Let me tell you
one more thing...
Sai is the name I was given
just for this mission...
この任務のためだけに
与えられた 名。
ボクは 誰でもない。
I'm nobody.
ボクは ダンゾウ様の手足だ。
I'm a tool for Lord Danzo.
ボクは 存在しない。
I don't exist.
だから ボクに 何を言っても
無意味なんだよ。
So no matter what you say
to me, it's pointless.
だったら… だったら なぜ➡
Then...
Then why...
その絵本を 大事に持ってるの？
do you hold on to
that picture book with such care?!
その表紙の ２人の子供
あなたと お兄さんでしょ？
The two kids on the cover...
are you and
your older brother, right?
なぜ その絵本を
大事に持ってるか➡
You're holding on to
that picture book with such care...
それは あなたの存在を 唯一
証明するものだからじゃないの？
because it's the only thing
that proves your existence, isn't it?
あなたは… 言うほど
感情を捨てきれていない。
You haven't been able to discard
your emotions as completely as you say.
(サクラ)忍だって 感情を
捨てきることは できないのよ。
Even Shinobi can't completely
discard their emotions.
(サクラ)その証拠に さっき
私が 絵本を差し出したとき➡
As proof of that...
when I handed
the picture book to you earlier...
あなたは 「ありがとう」って言って
それを受け取ったのよ。
You said thanks and took it.
自分の存在を
証明できる絵本が➡
You were relieved to get back...
手元に戻ってきたことに
安堵した。
the picture book that can prove
your existence.
(サイ)なぜ
この絵本を持ってることが➡
Why does having this picture book
prove my own existence?
自分の存在を
証明することになるんですか？
あなたが その本を
手放したくない理由…➡
The reason why you don't want
to part with that book...
それは 弟としての自分を
捨てることができないでいるから。
is that you can't forsake yourself
as a younger brother...
なぜだか わかる？
Do you know why?
あなたにとっては それだけ
お兄さんとの つながりが➡
It's because your bonds with
your older brother...
大切だったからよ。
were that important to you!
あなたは お兄さんとのつながりを
消したくないと思ってる。
You don't want to erase the bonds
you have with your older brother...
つながり…。
Bonds...
悪いけど 絵本の中身は
見せてもらったよ。
Sorry, but we had a look
inside the picture book.
(ヤマト)中央の見開きだけ
絵が 未完成になってる。
Only the picture in
the center-facing pages is unfinished.
サイ… キミが 暗部の根の者
だってことも知ってる。
Sai... I also know that you're
from The Foundation.
ダンゾウによって 感情を殺すための➡
And I also know that
you received special training...
特別な訓練を
受けていたことも 知ってる。
from Danzo in order
to suppress your emotions.
特別な訓練…？
Special training...?
感情を奪うために➡
It's the same as the evil practice...
血霧の里 霧隠れで かつて
行われていた 悪習と同じだ。
once conducted in the Village Hidden
in the Mist a.k.a. Blood Mist Village,
in order to take away emotions.
血霧の里… 霧隠れ…。
The Blood Mist Village ...
The Hidden Mist...?
それって 再不斬の…！
That's where Zabuza's from!
それじゃ…。
Then...
((カカシ : その昔…
血霧の里と呼ばれた➡
A long time ago...
in the Village Hidden in the Mist
a.k.a. Blood Mist Village,
霧隠れの里には…➡
忍者になるための
最大の難関が あった。
there was an extremely difficult obstacle
in order to become Ninja.
(再不斬)フン… あの卒業試験まで
知っているのか？
You even know about
that graduation exam...?
あの卒業試験？
That graduation exam?
フッフッフ…。
おい なんなんだってばよ！
What's that graduation exam?
あの卒業試験って…。
フッフッフ…。
生徒どうしの殺し合いだ。
Fellow students kill each other.
(再不斬)同じ釜の飯を食った
仲間どうしが➡
Fellow comrades who all ate
from the same bowl...
２人１組になり やりあう…。
make teams of two
and fight each other...
どちらかの命 尽きるまで…。
until one of them dies.
それまで助け合い 夢を語り合い➡
Comrades who until that point
would help each other,
talk about their dreams
and compete with each other...
(競い合った仲間だ…))
絵本の流れからいくと➡
Looking at the flow
of the picture book,
キミが敵を倒していき
戦った敵の武器や鎧を➡
it appears you're
defeating enemies...
and taking away
their weapons and armor...
奪い取っていっているようだ。
中央の見開きで
キミとお兄さんが戦うことになる。
On the facing pages at the center...
you will end up fighting
your older brother...
キミは お兄さんを…。
You killed your older brother--
違う。
No!
これは 兄さんに
プレゼントするつもりだった。
I was planning on
giving this to him.
でも もう少しで
絵本が完成するってときに➡
But when I was just about finished
with the picture book, he...
兄さんは…。
He...
(サイ)兄さんは…。
病気で死んだ。
died from sickness.
((何も感じないって…➡
What do you mean...you don't feel
anything or have any emotions?
感情がないって どういうこと？
言葉どおり そういうことだよ。
I mean just what I said.
だからって…➡
Even so...
あなたも兄弟がいるなら➡
If you have a brother,
you should be able to imagine...
その兄弟が
いなくなったときのこと➡
少しは想像できるでしょう？
what it would be like
to lose him, right?
ん？ あぁ…。
Yeah, well...you could say that...
まあね… 兄さん もう死んでるし。
My brother's dead, after all.
だったら 余計に…。
Then all the more...
I wonder if I should've
looked like that.
ああいう顔をすれば
よかったのかな？
えっ？
何が言いたいの？
What're you trying to say?
いやね… 兄さんが死んだときに➡
Well... I didn't know what kind
of look to make
(どういう顔を作ればいいか
わからなかったから))
when my brother died...
In The Foundation, there were
many children of broken families...
(サイ)根には 戦いで生じた
離散家族の子が 多くいてね。
brought about by battle.
そのなかで 兄弟のように
親しくなったのが➡
He was one of those children.
I became close with him,
like a brother.
兄さんだった…。
We weren't related by blood...
(サイ)血はつながって
なかったけど➡
ボクの絵を よく ほめてくれたんだ。
But he often said nice things
about my drawings.
In this picture book...
この絵本… 兄さんに
いちばん見せたかったのは➡
what I wanted to show him
most of all...
最後の見開きの絵だった
はずなんだけど…。
was what were supposed to be the final
pictures on the facing pages.
兄さんが死んでから➡
But after he died...
何を描こうとしていたのか
思い出せないんだ…。
I couldn't remember
what I was going to draw.
Unfortunately Sai...
残念だけど サイ…。
キミはここで 分身のボクに➡
I'll be having my clone
stand guard over you here.
見張らせておくよ。
よし… こっから
仕切りなおしだってばよ。
All right!
Now it's back to square one...
サスケを助けだす！
We're going to save Sasuke!
やめたほうがいいよ。
I wouldn't bother.
ボクは…➡
I...
サスケ君に会った。
met Sasuke.
サスケ君には
常に大蛇丸がついている。
Sasuke always has Orochimaru
with him.
すなわち 再び大蛇丸と➡
That is to say, you'll have to fight
Orochimaru once again.
やり合わなければ
ならないということだ。
深追いすれば バラバラにされて➡
You'll end up being
chopped up into pieces...
and turned into a test subject
if you pursue reckssly.
実験体になるのがオチだよ。
それに…。
And...
それに… なんだってばよ！
And what?!
サスケ君は
キミのことを 何でもないと言った。
Sasuke said he doesn't care
about you...
サクラさんは キミがサスケ君のことを➡
Sakura said you think of Sasuke like
a brother.
兄弟のように思っていると
言っていた。
それなのに…。
And yet...
(サイ)そんな彼のことを
キミは どうして…。
For a guy like that, why...?
どうして
あの大蛇丸に はむかってまで➡
Why are you trying
to get him back...
命をかけてまで
連れ戻そうとするんだ？
なぜなんだ？
誰に命令されているわけでも
ないのに…。
昔 オレは サスケのことが
大嫌いだった！
アイツもオレも 家族がいないのは
同じだったのに…。
アイツはエリートで オレは万年ドベだった。
でも 一緒にいて ほんとは
すごく楽しかったんだってばよ！
アイツは…。
アイツは 誰よりもオレのことを
認めてくれた一人だ。
サスケは オレの友達だ。
やっとできた 大切なつながりだ。
つながり？
だからって➡
だからって 大蛇丸を相手に…。
相手が誰だろうと
関係ねえってばよ！
腕がもがれりゃ 蹴り倒す！
脚がもがれりゃ 噛み倒す！
首がもがれりゃ 睨み倒す！
目がもがれりゃ 呪い倒す！
たとえ バラバラにされようが➡
オレは 大蛇丸から➡
サスケを
奪い返してやるんだってばよ！
なぁ ヤマト隊長
さっき飲んだ種なんだけどさ。
(ヤマト)ん？ 何？
ぶっちゃけ 効果って
いつまで続くもんなの？
もう そんなの
どうだっていいでしょ！
いや だってさ➡
今みたいなときは
便利だろうけど➡
オレら ずっと任務に
ついてるわけじゃないし➡
いくら隊長にだって➡
ふだんの行動が
全部 筒抜けになっちまうのは➡
さすがに ちょっと困るってばよ！
あぁ それなら心配ないよ。
いつまでも相手の行動を
把握できるわけじゃないし。
それって
具体的に言うと どのくらい？
まぁ 種が体内にとどまれるのは
せいぜい２～３日くらいかな。
な～んだ そんなもんか！
ってことは あれ？
最終的には やっぱ便所から…。
まぁ そうとわかれば
安心だってばよ！
いやぁ よかったなぁ サクラちゃん！
お前は まず デリカシーを学べ！
フガッ！